So we're almost at the finish line.
But to get to the finish line, you need a start line.
And that's exactly what we're doing in this lesson.
We'll be adding in a start screen.
As you know, with our game development workflow, the first thing we need to do is think about how
it's going to look and how it's going to work.
Thinking about it, what we simply want is a nice looking screen.
That is the first thing that appears when we start the game.
So with that 30s idea dropped out of the way, we can move on to step two, which is laying out the
foundation.
So first things first, let's bring in our main backdrop for our start screen.
And for this we can use our main stage.
So clicking on it and then backdrops.
You'll notice that we don't have any backdrops at the moment.
However, because we are simulating snow, we are just using blank white backdrop.
So keep that in mind.
So clicking the import button, then moving to the folder start screen, we can select these two start
screen files and hit open.
Here.
As you can see, we have this animation that flickers.
You are here text, but as you can see, is this big empty gap at the bottom of our start screen.
So this is where we want to add a nice little animation that plays with trees.
So for all these trees, we could technically import them into our background.
However, because we want to create a nice layered effect, we are going to make it a new sprite.
So again, uploading a new sprite here you'll see we have this tree line sprite over here.
So selecting that and hitting open there you can see some nice trees.
Now what we want is for these trees to move over to the left and then back to the right, which will
create our animation.
The only problem, however, is our trees are pretty much the exact size of the screen.
So there's little room to move them.
So what do we do?
Well, we have two options to fix this.
We could either scale them up, which would work, but even better, if we move over to the costume
editor and click this button Convert to Vector.
Selecting this tool, what we can now do is move it all over to the right, copy it, and then paste.
And then we can try and get it to somewhat line up.
So with this tree line done we can duplicate the sprite.
So we can have two tree lines.
Now we need to do is add in our start button.
Once again hitting upload we can select the start button image.
And there you have it a gigantic start button.
Great.
But before we try write any proper code, let's organize all this so we actually have an idea of what's
going on.
Firstly, let's fix this start button.
I think that here 25 is a much more realistic size.
So with that you can just move it to the bottom here.
And finally for our trees we want it to be something like this.
So this tree line should cover this a blank space.
And then this bottom tree line needs to be in the very front.
So it covers our start button just a bit which gives us a nice layered effect.
Well that's basically it for now.
Our sprites are imported.
Everything is in place.
Now all we need to do is get coding.
So prepare yourself because it's about to start.